Argha Karmakar

Sr. Manager - Strategy, Marketing & MarCom

A young, enthusiastic, disciplined, honest & hardworking professional with 8+ years of experience in Auto & Aero Industry, accompanied by positive attitude, open to learn & relocate, work and grow, full of sportsman spirit and a leader by choice. I am a target oriented, fully committed, energetic, ambitious, decisive & self motivated person, having very high expectations for myself which urges me to extend all aspects of my performance to explore and expand the boundaries of my own potential.



arghakarmakar1992@gmail.com



9023604903



Gurugram, India



in linkedin.com/in/arghak3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Manager - Marketing & MarCom Böllhoff Fastenings Pvt. Ltd.

04/2021 - Present Gurugram - Haryana German MNC special fastening solutions & assembly technologies Achievements/Tasks

- Launched B2C product International Market worth 18 Cr
- B2B Growth Strategy 36% increased revenue in 2023-24
- Established marketing communications from scratch (Digital marketing & conventional communications)

Dy. Manager - Marketing & MarCom Komax Automation India Pvt. Ltd.

05/2019 - 03/2021 Gurugram - Haryana Swiss MNC complete automation solutions for wire processing Achievements/Tasks

- Launched 3 successful B2B products in span of 2 years
- Corporate strategy formulation for Automotive & General
- Managed all public communications for pan India

Officer - Marketing & Sales **Subros Limited**

11/2016 - 04/2019 Noida - Uttar Pradesh Indian Firm Manufacturer of thermal products for automotive sector Achievements/Tasks

- Converted 5 major PV businesses in 2 year M&M | TML
- Assessed market potential & gather market intelligence

BDA - Byju's: The Learning App Think and Learn Pvt. Ltd.

03/2016 - 10/2016 Bangalore - Karnataka Indian Firm educational technology and online tutoring platform Achievements/Tasks

 New business development / Lead generation / Marketing management / Sales Analyst

CERTIFICATES

MarCom - MSBM, UK | Corporate Strategy - IIM, Bangalore (04/2020 - 10/2023) Online course via Swayam - Govt. of India

EDUCATION

06/2011 - 06/2016

B. Tech (ME) + MBA (Marketing) Lovely Professional University

SKILLS

Marketing Strategy Business Strategy Marketing Communications Project Management

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Senior Under Officer

National Cadet Corps. (NCC - LPU)

03/2016 - 03/2016 Jalandhar - Punjab NCC - youth wing of armed forces, second line of defence in India. Tasks/Achievements

- "CEE" Certificate Holder with "A" Grade
- Leadership Management
- Cadet & Camp Administration with more than 2000+ cadets

ORGANIZATIONS

Steerme: Start-up Online Student Counselling (Free) (03/2017 - Present)

Guiding freshers and students to take a career path of their interest.

HONOR AWARDS

Visharad (Music - Tabla : Indian Classical Music) (01/2000 - Present)

Akhil Bharatiya Gandharva Mahavidyalaya Mandal, Miraj

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Bengali

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Tabla

Football

Travelling

Cricket

Jalandhar - Puniab

ARGHA KARMAKAR

Phone: +91 90236 04903 arghakarmakar1992@gmail.com House no. 1777, Sector 10A, Gurugram Haryana, 122001

Objective:

Play a pivotal role in developing, shaping, and executing the Business Strategy, Marketing & Communications activities, with a holistic & innovative approach, in context of relevant market intelligence. Make the best use of my attitude, expertise, skills, and extensive experience, utilized to add value towards leading organizational growth targets of increasing revenue, market share and positive work culture accompanied by repute and ethics.

Value Offered:

A young, disciplined, honest & hardworking person with positive attitude, open to learn, work and grow, full of sportsmanship spirit and a leader by example.

Key Skills:

Marketing Strategy	PR & Communications	Project Management	Leadership
Digital Marketing	Corporate Strategy	Product Management	Market Intelligence

EDUCATION				
B. Tech (ME) + MBA (Marketing + Operations) June 2016				
	Lovely Professional University, Punjab Integrated dual degree, UGC – 7.96 CGPA			
12 th	Somerville School, Greater Noida Higher Secondary School, CBSE – 72%	May 2011		
10 th	Somerville School, Greater Noida Secondary School, CBSE – 89%	May 2009		
PROFESS	IONAL CERTIFICATIONS			
Corporate Strategy IIM, Bangalore		2023		
Marketing Communications MSBM, UK		2021		
Digital Marketing Udemy, Shaw Academy		2020		

Curriculum Vitae

WORK CULTURE HIGHLIGHTS

- Extensive experience in heading the Marketing Department for MNCs
- Direct reporting to Managing Director, Board members
- Leading and inspiring a team of 5 international marketing professionals, taking care of Strategy Communications Product management Digital Marketing.
- Strong leadership skills with abilities to develop & execute marketing strategies & campaigns with cross functional teams to leverage diverse expertise.
- A go-getter, result-oriented, with a positive & innovative approach

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bollhoff Fastenings Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram

Apr' 2021 - Present

Promotions : Manager \rightarrow Sr. Manager – Marketing

1. Business Strategy:

- Business & Corporate Strategy formulation and implementation as Chief Strategist
- Working closely with the leadership team to formulate the business's medium to long term financial and strategic plan.
- Work with business unit heads to build their annual budgets and forecasts.
- Responsible for consolidating strategic measures in board management meeting.
- Ensure project timelines for implementation and execution of strategic actions.
- Analyze & circulate various economic, business trends and outlook in domestic and Asian market China, South-east countries like Vietnam, Indonesia & Singapore.
- Prepare illustrative presentations of economic outlook, company financial performance, ESG activities and status on keys strategies to management.
- Responsible for business acquisitions by analysis of past performance of the company for valuation based on outlook.
- Have a big picture thinking and analytical ability to perform strategic innovation.
- Coordinate with senior management to consolidate data and work on out-of-the-box ideas to reduce bottlenecks and streamline processes for smooth functioning and maximizing profitability.
- Understanding key businesses drivers as well as identifying, and managing key issues and risks through insights, factual conclusions, and advice.
- Prepare Product cost analysis of the business.
- Preparing business cases to support new investment, strategic and other business decisions.
- Communicating results and recommendations to senior management for improvements that will lead to cost optimization, revenue generation and streamlining operations.
- Provide insights to senior management around financial modelling, forecasts, and profitability.
- Growth entry strategy, GTM, market sizing & opportunity analysis, competition analysis, assessing business models / value chain dynamics.
- Good understanding of business processes and functions.
- Develop structures processes for business growth that are aligned with business rhythm, investment strategies and innovation strategies.

Curriculum Vitae

2. Marketing Strategy:

- 360° Marketing with innovative Go-to-market Strategies & Brand custodian
- Developed & Executed marketing plans to achieve company goals
- Responsible for marketing collaterals development, seminars management
- Public relations management PAN India with impactful communication strategies
- Media Management with nurturing key contacts in the automotive, aerospace & general industry
- Digital Marketing: Social Media Campaigns, SEO, SMM, Website handling
- Vendor management: Coordination with Media agencies, Content developers
- Developed & implemented Brand Management campaigns
- Exhibitions / Event management (internal & external)
- Developed & maintained relationships with key stakeholders
- Annual marketing budget & sourcing
- Conducting Market Research and Intelligence in the industry
- Expertise in handling B2B marketing agencies, content strategy both online & offline
- Competitor Intelligence & Customer Legal Agreements Analysis
- Increased revenue & market share through effective marketing strategies
- Close tracking systems for lead management and identification of new leads generation process and ideas
- Ensure efficient handling of Marketing operations tools and outsourced assets
- Overall customer service responsibilities via brand surveys & customer surveys
- Overseeing business development, new product development and new application activities for new areas of strategic & organic growth.
- Contribution towards new avenues in corporate social responsibility activities
- Collaborate with sales, engineering, and operations teams to ensure alignment and execution of product strategies.
- Serve as the primary point of contact for key stakeholders, including senior leadership, customers, and partners.
- Fostering a culture of achievement, motivation, and excellence within the team.
- Conducting regular review meetings with cross functional teams to adjust strategies, track progress, address challenges to meet evolving market demands.

Komax Automation India Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram

May' 2019 to Mar' 2021

Deputy Manager – Marketing (PM)

- Supervising a team of marketing professionals including Swiss HQ
- Increasing brand awareness and absorbing technology to develop marketing strategy
- Developing & implementing Business Strategies for increasing revenue streams
- Innovative development & execution of Marketing communications
- Market research & competition intelligence
- 360° Digital Marketing: SMM, SEO & Website Handling
- Exhibitions & Event management Online & Offline platforms
- Expertise in handling B2B marketing agencies, content strategy both online & offline
- Competitor Intelligence & Customer Legal Agreements Analysis
- Annual marketing budget & sourcing

- Close tracking systems for lead management and identification of new leads generation process and ideas
- Responsible for marketing collaterals development, seminars management
- Developed & maintained relationships with key stakeholders
- Contribution towards new avenues in corporate social responsibility activities
- Establish KPIs / metrics to track the success of product initiatives & measure progress

Subros Ltd., Noida

Nov' 2016 to Apr' 2019

Promotions : Officer → Sr. Engineer – Sales & Marketing

- Project Co-ordination: OE Passenger vehicle segment
- Program Management: OE Passenger vehicle segment
- Customer Engagement & MIS preparations
- Assessing market potential
- Market research and intelligence for air conditioning demand & customer requirements
- Exhibitions & Event management Online & Offline platforms
- Competitor Intelligence & Customer Legal Agreements Analysis
- Contribution towards new avenues in corporate social responsibility activities
- Introduction and promotion of new products in the market, emphasizing their USPs.

Byju's: The learning App, Bengaluru

Mar' 2016 to Oct' 2016

BDA – Sales & Marketing

- Building market position by locating, negotiating, and closing business relationships.
- Locating/proposing potential business deals for the company & exploring opportunities.
- Identify potential buyers for various company products and closing on sales.
- Building and maintaining business relationships with high level executives.
- Customer success relationship
- Innovatively crack down on various ideas to generate revenue / promotional activities
- Contribution towards new avenues in corporate social responsibility activities
- Customer account management with the help of sales CRM software, and key matrix.

INTERNSHIPS – ENGINEERING & MANAGEMENT

Organization: Oerlikon Graziano

June 2015 to July 2015

Management Trainee

• Oerlikon Operations – Analysis of prevailing system and implementation of Value stream mapping in the shop floor.

Organization: Oerlikon Graziano

June 2014 to July 2014

Engineer Trainee

• Oerlikon Production – Analysis of Labor-intensive assembly line, aiming to increase efficiency of the system using FLB (Flexible Line Balancing Method).

Curriculum Vitae

Engineer Trainee

• Delphi R&D – to study the effect of airflow experienced by the condenser and further recommending improvements.

PROJECTS - ENGINEERING

Capstone Title

Vortex Induced Vibrations for Aquatic Clean Energy (V.I.V.A.C.E) Convertor

Objective

To evaluate and analyze the design of the prevailing VIVACE Convertor equipment and come up with a more emphasized and efficient model of the equipment.

Deliverables

Computer aided design & analysis, prototyping & development of the equipment.

COMPUTER SKILLS

- SAP SD Module | Infor M3 ERP | MS Dynamics
- MS Office 365 | MATE LinkedIn | YT | Leadsquared | JIRA Project Mgmt.

CERTIFICATIONS (COLLEGE / SCHOOL)

- Visharad in Music (Tabla), Gandharva Mahavidyalaya, New Delhi, May 2011.
- NCC "C" Certificate, "A" Grade, National Cadet Corps., Punjab, 2013 2016.

LEADERSHIP ROLES & MISCELLANEOUS ACHIEVEMENTS

Graduation & Post Graduation

- 2nd Prize "National Level summer internship competition", Ganpat University, Gujarat, 2016.
- 1st Prize Intra University Instrumental Competition, Concoction 2014-15.
- Placement Coordinator, 2014-15
- Class Representative, B. tech + MBA, for consecutive years 2011 2016.
- Senior Under Officer NCC, LPU 2015-16.
- Under Officer NCC, LPU 2014-15.
- Escorted International Level Delegates, LPU 2013 2016.
- Winner National Level Best Cadet Advanced Leadership Camp NCC 2015.
- Attended and organized NCC Camps at different locations in Punjab, Haryana & Himachal.
- Former member ASME American Society for Mechanical Engineers, 2014 2016.
- Captain Football Team, Lovely school of mechanical engineering, 2011 2015.

Higher Secondary School	 Head Boy – Annual House Report, handling a team of 250+ students. Worked as a "Musician", All India Radio, New Delhi, 2010 – 2011. Winner – National Level Instrumental competition – Sitare, Greater Noida, 2011. 2nd Prize, Annual Inter-house Elocution competition at Army School, Noida. 1st Position, physical education, Somerville School 100 mtrs. Best Sports Person – Football, Somerville School.
Secondary School	 Director's Prize – Music (Tabla), Alaknanda Institute of performing arts Winner, District-level instrumental competition representing Somerville School, Greater Noida. Winner, Inter-school elocution competitions representing Somerville School. Winner, Inter-school Instrumental competitions representing Somerville School. Winner, Inter-school Football tournament representing as a Team Captain.

FAMILY

My father. Mr. Deb Nath Karmakar retired as an Admin Manager, C&S Electric. My mother, Mrs. Krishna Karmakar, is a teacher by profession, to retire this year. My sister Ms. Arpita Karmakar, is a Psychologist at Max Hospital, Saket. My wife, Ms. Soumita Karmakar, is also working as a teacher, with her education in B.A. + M.A. + B. Ed (English Hons.) & My son, Ayan, just came to this world 2 years back.

References would be provided on request.

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to best of my knowledge.

Argha Karmakar